Huasong Shan

Contact Information 4707 Tigerland Ave., Apt. 45 Baton Rouge, LA 70820

1-225-228-5446

monadynshy@outlook.com

https://monadyn.github.io/

SUMMARY

I have more than 10 years experience in performance and security of large-scale web applications, cloud computing, data mining, database and telecommunication. My work philosophy is "show me the code, show me the data, and show me the graph", put everything visible. Based-on this philosophy I have built tools for project management, version control and quality management, log anomaly detection, performance bottleneck detection, intrusion detection.

EDUCATION

Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA, US

Ph.D., Computer Science, Dec 2017

• Dissertation: Very Short Intermittent DDoS Attacks on the Performance of Web Services in Clouds

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China

M.S./B.S., Computer Science, Jun 2016/Jun 2003

• Thesis: Research of Mandatory Access Control for SDM4 Object Features

TECH SKILLS

- Java, Python, C, Bash, Make, JavaScript, SQL
- NumPy, Pandas, Trac, Django, Jenkins, Bitten, PhantomJS, d3.js
- OpenStack, Docker, AWS SDKs & CLI Tools, Azure, PackStack, Puppet
- Hadoop, Kafka, SVM, Reinforcement Learning, Kalman Filter

Work EXPERIENCES

Research Assistant

Aug 2015 to Dec 2017

lsuCloud, Computer Science and Engineering Division, Louisiana State University Jan 2016 to Dec 2016 Research Assistant

Center for Computation and Technology, Louisiana State University

Staff Software Engineer

Jan 2008 to Aug 2015

Infrastructure and System Department, Spreadtrum Communications, Inc.

Software Test Engineer

Sept 2006 to Dec 2007

Shanghai Research Institute, ZTE

ACCOMPLISHMENT Student Travel Grant

& Awards

• ACM CCS'17

Oct 2017

Project Timely Awards — Spreadtrum Communications, Inc.

• for Data Mining System for Log Anomaly Detection

Dec 2014

- for Automated Build and Test Platform
- as a certificate platform Dec 2011
- for Capturing terminal real-time debugging info. in SD-Card as a patent Oct 2008

Project EXPERIENCE Performance Bottlenecks Diagnosis Platform in Distributed Systems

2015-2017

- Transform performance bottlenecks into visibility
- Adapt monitor tools(e.g., OProfile, Collectl, WireShark, Logs of Apache and MySQL)

Memory Contention Profiling and Performance Impact in Multi-tenant Clouds 2017

- Profile memory contention and performance interference in Co-located VMs
- Saturate memory bus and lock memory bus in modern CPU architecture

Performance Eval. and Predict for Long-tail Model in Distributed Systems 2016-2017

- Optimize model parameters using feedback control theory (e.g., Kalman filter) and machine learning (e.g., reinforcement learning)
- Evaluate the model in simulations by modify Java modeling tools

User Behavior Model Validation to Detect Bots

2015-2016

- Distinguish bots from legitimate users using machine learning (e.g., SVM)
- Model user behaviors of navigating websites

Capacity Prediction and Application Layer Anomaly Detection

2015-2016

- Detect anomaly on HTTP layer modifying Snort and Snort.AD
- Profile the performance and capacity of target website in the wild

Container-based Hybrid Cloud Orchestration

2016

- Manage resources in hybrid-clouds using AWS SDK (Boto3), Docker Swarm, Mesos
- Automatically generate images of MPI applications using Dockerfile

Data Mining System for Log Anomaly Detection

2014-2015

- Transform log anomaly into visibility
- Crawl binary logs using Bugzilla RESTful API
- Parse and clean binary log into XML format using C
- Analysis log anomaly by regular match algorithm in time-line event
- Visualize results with event flow graph using d3.js
- Manage data using NoSQL database MongoDB
- Implement standalone version using PyQT
- Implement online version using JavaScript with WebSocket

Data Mining System for Project Management

2013

- Transform engineers' work efficiency into visibility
- Extract original data using Bugzilla RESTful API from bug tracking database
- Filter data using NumPy/Pandas
- Define new metrics to quantify requirements (e.g. speed of bug processing)
- Visualize statistics results using d3.js

Automated Parallel and Distributed Build and Test Platform

2009-2012

- Transform quality management and version control into visibility
- Build simulation platform for the protocol software of mobile phones in Windows
- Customized distributed build by modifying the code of Jenkins and Bitten
- Distributed parallel test, achieving to finish tens of thousands test cases within 0.5h
- Manage build and test clusters (hundreds of computers) using state machine pattern

Real-time Capturing Terminal Debugging Information in Flash (SD-card)

2008

- Manage critical debugging information using circle buff
- Optimize write efficiency of SIO in SD-card

Patents

1. **Huasong Shan** "Method and terminal device for capturing terminal debugging information in real-time manner". Appl. No. CN101945155 A, 2011.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Huasong Shan**, Qingyang Wang, and Calton Pu. "Tail Attacks on Web Applications" in Proc. of the 24th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS'17), Dallas, Texas, October 30-November 3, 2017. (top tier security conference)
- 2. **Huasong Shan**, Qingyang Wang, and Qiben Yan. "Very Short Intermittent DDoS Attacks in an Unsaturated System" in Proc. of the 13th EAI International Conference on Security and Privacy in Communication Networks (Secure Comm'17), Niagara Falls, Canada, October 22-24, 2017.